Hello everyone, welcome back to today's another new tutorial topic. So today here, I will create
the MySQL tutorial. So today I will going to explore the unit constant in MySQL. It's a powerful
feature for ensuring data in security in your database. Okay, so first I'll simply explain for
the MySQL in it constant. This means that no two rows can have the same value for the column.
So now let's explore how it works with some example. Okay, so first of all here I create the
simple table with the unit constant. Okay, so here I already created the table structure. So create
table name for the student and the student's ID and the student's name and here I can create for
the email. Okay, so in this email column must contain unit values that ensure that the student
email address unique within the table and a term is made to insert the duplicate email address
into this column. Okay, so now just here CNET and execution now wait, you can see here this table
is completely created and show the confirmation message for this comment is completely
successful. Okay, and next up here I can modify the existing column to 3 unique key grid. Okay,
so the next step here I can open another new query and first of all I can just type this is the
alter or here the table suppose like students. So it is called the student's table and here
I can just use for and constants. Okay, so now just here I can type this is the cons
t R a and t. So this is the as constant for unit email. Okay, so u and i q e v. Okay, so unique
underscore this email column. So here I can just again use the q u v. So the unique and in this case
define for the unique. Okay, so now here completely defined and this statement using for the algorithm
the statement to add a unique constant name for the unit to the email column in the students
table. Okay, so now just I can select all and execute in this table and you can see here
this comment is completely successful. Okay, so here completely made to modify the column
to allow the duplicate values. Okay, and now here the next step just I can insert the data
into the table with the unique constant. Okay, so open another query and first of all I can type
this is the insert and here select for the table's name students. Okay, so different for the students
and in this insert first of all I can define this is the just going here first of all clear the
students are okay. So just define the students underscore ID and next step here I can insert for the
students name. Professor different underscore students name column and also here the students
email. Okay, so EMA I look at perfectly explained and now next step here I can just define this
is the values. Okay, so the students are somehow so first of all here I can define it for the students
ID1 and then define for the name of Johan and also here I can create for the email address
suppose my Johan at the rate gmail.com. Okay, so now here perfectly different and now clear this
semicolor and now just inserting for some some whole data query and now I can just select
then execute and you can see here completely if you know it's affected. So now just here
I can open for the new query so just go here and then first of all I can select then
start from here the table's name and students. Okay, so just verify for the students and just
click the email. Okay, so now insert and you can see here completely use the students ID name and
the email and in the email for the unicorn. Okay, and they are completely used for it is called the
unique statement. Okay, so here the session is completely done and the complete overview of the
unique constraint in the MySQL for some practical example. So I hope you perfectly understand
the studio is completely helpful. So stay tuned for more MySQL tips and tricks. Okay,
So, thank you for watching, ok.